Franklin R. Weissberg Papers
Franklin R. Weissberg Papers
1966-1967
Weissberg, Franklin R.
5.0 linear feet
Papers of the New York attorney, relating to the 1967 New York State Constitutional Convention. Weissberg was a delegate to the convention from the 26th senatorial district, New York County. Collection includes correspondence, memorabilia, writings, New York State Constitutional committee papers and miscellany.
148743
Biographical History
Franklin R. Weissberg (1931- ) is a New York attorney, litigator, and judge.
Born in New York City, Weissberg attended Bronx High School of Science and graduated from Syracuse University with an A.B. degree in 1952. In 1954-1955 he was on active duty as a corporal with the U.S. Army Artillery in Germany. He received an LLB degree from Harvard Law School in 1957, and from 1960 to 1961 served as law secretary to Supreme Court Justice Edgar J. Nathan, Jr. of New York County.
Early in his career Weissberg practiced law in New York City with the firm of Colton, Fernbach and Weissberg; later he was a member of the Temporary State Commission on the Cultural Resources of the State (1972-1973), President of the Association of Court of Claims Judges of the State of New York (1992-1999), Acting Justice of the Supreme Court, New York County (1986-2001), and Judge for the New York State Court of Claims (1986-2001). He is presently (2009) of counsel for the firm of Lowenstein Sandler PC.
Weissberg's activities in the Republican Party include serving as district leader of the 66th Assembly District of the New York Republican organization and as Mayor John V. Lindsay's Special Consultant for the Performing Arts. He was an elected delegate to the 1967 New York State Constitutional Convention from the 26th District, and served on the Committee on the Executive Branch and the Committee on the Legislature.
He is a member of the New York State Bar Association, the New York County Lawyers Association, and the Association of Court of Claims Judges of the State of New York. He has also lectured on litigation matters at numerous seminars and law institutes.
[Portions of this biographical sketch obtained from Weissberg's profile on the Lowenstein Sandler PC website, http://www.lowenstein.com/fweissberg/.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Franklin R. Weissberg Papers consist of correspondence, memorabilia, writings, New York State Constitutional Convention issues and committee materials, and miscellaneous printed material.
The Correspondence is with constituents, Constitutional Convention delegates, lawyers, statesmen, politicians and friends, and relates to convention and convention committee business. Issues discussed include taxes (especially real estate taxes and their possible effects in New York City), natural resources, judicial appointments, the Blaine Amendment, welfare, the grand jury system, and education. Outgoing letters contain definite and positive opinions. Significant correspondents include Vincent J. Albano, the American Bar Association, Earl W. Brydges, James F. Carroll, Paul Fino, S. William Green, Roswell B. Perkins, J. Irwin Shapiro and Robert Sweet.
Memorabilia consists of biographical material.
Writings include letters to the editor, a speech, statements and a television interview.
New York State Constitutional Convention issues and committee material consist of committee minutes, reproduced typescripts and printed copies of propositions, reports, statements, reproductions of typescript memoranda, position papers and a small number of holograph notes. The Bill of Rights folder contains typescript notes of a telephone conversation between Weissberg and Arnold G. Fraiman on wire tapping.
Miscellaneous printed material includes reports, periodicals and pamphlets on subjects of interest to the 1967 New York State Constitutional Convention. It is arranged alphabetically by author or originating agency.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged chronologically. Writings are arramged alphabetically by type. Constitutional convention material is arranged alphabetically by topic. Printed material is arranged alphabetically by author.
Related Material
For additional material relating to the 1967 New York State Constitutional Convention, see also the
Erastus Corning II Papers
and the
Leonard B. Sand Papers
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Politics, government and public administration; Weissberg, Franklin R.; New York (State). -- Constitutional Convention (1967); Constitutional conventions -- New York (State); New York (State) -- Politics and government, 1951-; Correspondence.; Minutes (administrative records); Reports.; Speeches (documents)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Franklin R. Weissberg, 1968.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - December 1966-November 1967, 4 folders (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Letters to the editor, New York Times, See correspondence, Aug. 31 and Sept. 18, 1967.
  - Speech to 1967 New York State Constitutional Convention, May 22, 1967; original typescript revised (Box 1)
  - Statement, "In Support of Resolution Barring Judges as Delegates to Future Constitutional Conventions", June 6, 1967; original typescript, including background material (Box 1)
  - Statement for New York City Mayor John V. Lindsay, "Progress of the Constitutional Convention," by Franklin R. Weissberg, Aug. 15, 1967; includes cover letter (Box 1)
  - Television broadcast, Franklin R. Weissberg, guest, Aug. 13, 1967; reproduction of typescript (Box 1)
- 1967 New York State Constitutional Convention
  - Bibliography (Box 1)
  - Bill of Rights, includes typescript notes of a telephone conversation With Arnold G. Fraiman (Box 2)
  - Blaine Amendment (Box 2)
  - Civil Service (Box 2)
  - Committee on Economic Development (Box 2)
  - Committee on the Executive Branch
    - Typescript minutes of meetings, memoranda (Box 2)
    - Propositions, typescript, reproduction, reprints (Box 2)
    - Propositions, printed (Box 2)
    - Public hearings, includes holograph notes (Box 3)
    - Sub-committee on Administrative Rules and Procedures, includes holograph notes (Box 3)
  - Committee on Intergovernmental Relations (Box 3)
  - Committee on the Legislature
    - Typescript minutes, propositions, reports, includes holograph notes (Box 3)
    - Propositions, printed (Box 3)
    - Public hearings, includes holograph notes (Box 3)
    - Voting of F.R. Weissberg (Box 3)
    - Sub-committee on Local Apportionment
      - Minutes of meetings, holograph notes, reports, position papers (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Committee on Rules (Box 4)
  - Committee on State Finances (Box 4)
  - Committee on Style and Arrangement, third reading of propositions (Box 4)
  - Delegates (Box 4)
  - Education (Box 4)
  - Ethics and lobbying (Box 5)
  - Finances, taxation and expenditures (Box 5)
  - Health, housing and social services (Box 5)
  - The Judiciary, memoranda, reproduction of typescripts and miscellaneous articles, statements, speeches (Box 5)
  - Lindsay, Mayor John V. (Box 6)
  - Local government and home rule (Box 6)
  - Natural resources (Box 6)
  - New York State Constitution and government (Box 6)
  - Position papers and polls (Box 6)
  - Position papers, Citizens Union (Box 6)
  - Press releases from Anthony J. Travia (Box 7)
  - Procedures (Box 7)
  - Proposed constitution
    - Reproduction of typescript, including holograph notes (Box 7)
    - Printed copies, annotated (Box 7)
  - Propositions and typescript reports on propositions (Box 7)
  - Roll Call (Box 7)
  - Rules, including holograph notes (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous printed material
  - American Bar Association, Canons of Professional Ethics, Canons of Judicial Ethics, 1957 (Box 8)
  - American Bar Association, Reports of the Special Committee on the Constitutional Convention
    - Court Structure and Management (Box 8)
    - Removal of Judges (Box 8)
    - Selection of Judges (Box 8)
    - Constitutional Simplification (Box 8)
    - Local Government and Finance (Box 8)
    - State Finance, Taxation and Housing and Community Development (Box 8)
  - Association of the Bar of the City of New York
    - The Record, Jan. 1967 (Box 8)
    - The Record, March 1967 (Box 8)
  - Association of the Judges of the Family Court of the State of New York, Inc., Memorandum, April 15, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Citizens Tax Council
    - Constitutional Limitations on the Debt (Box 8)
    - Incurring and Real Property Taxing Powers of Municipalities Must be Retained (Box 8)
  - Committee for Economic Development, Modernizing State Government (Box 8)
  - County Officers Association, The County Finance Study Committee Report, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Harriss, C. Lowell, Constitutional Restrictions on Property Taxing and Borrowing Powers in New York (Box 8)
  - Hart, Walter R., Long Live the American Jury, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Keyserling, Leon H., No Increase in Property Taxes in New York City (Box 8)
  - Levitt, Arthur, State Comptroller
    - Annual Report of the Comptroller, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Basic Data on the Local Government and State-Local Relationships, Jan. 1967 (Box 8)
    - Constitutional Limitations on Municipal Dept., June 1967 (Box 8)
    - Financial Data for School Districts, 1966 (Box 8)
    - History of the Comptroller's Office (Box 8)
    - New York State Fiscal Affairs and Debt Structure, 1967 (Box 8)
    - State Aid to Local Government, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Tax Limits of School Districts in Cities, Feb. 1967 (Box 8)
    - Tax Limits of Counties, Cities and Villages, Oct. 1966 (Box 9)
  - Lindenbaum, Abraham M., Constitutional Provisions of Article VIII New York State Constitution Must Be Retained (Box 9)
  - Lowell, C. Stanley, The Hidden Wealth (Box 9)
  - Morris, James S. and O'Connor, Robert F., A Study of the Local Courts in Westchester County, 1967 (Box 9)
  - New York State Department of Taxation and Finance
    - Bulletin (Box 9)
    - The New York State and Local Tax System, 1964 (Box 9)
  - State of New York Division for Youth, Data on Youth, 1967 (Box 9)
  - State of New York Court of Claims, Annual Report, Jan. 18, 1967 (Box 9)
  - State of New York Joint Legislative Committee on Higher Education, Interim Report, 1967 (Box 9)
  - State of New York Department of Commerce, This is New York (Box 9)
  - State University Construction Fund, Annual Report, 1966 (Box 9)
  - State University of New York, Campus Plans (Box 9)
  - State of New York, Message to the Legislature and Inaugural Address, Nelson A. Rockefeller, governor, Jan. 2 and 4, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Temporary State Commission on the Constitutional Convention
    - 1. 1967 Convention Issues, Dec. 22, 1966 (Box 9)
    - 2. Toward an Effective Convention, Jan. 3, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 3. Local Finance, Jan. 27, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 4. The Right to Vote, Feb. 10, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 5. For Effective Constitutional Review, March 3, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 6. Education, March 3, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 7. Individual Liberties, March 16, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 8. State Finances, March 24, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 9. Housing, Labor, Natural Resources, March 24, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 10. Individual Freedoms, March 31, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 11. Welfare, Health and Mental Health, March 31, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 12. The Judiciary, March 31, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 13. State Government, March 31, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 14. Revision and Simplification, March 31, 1967 (Box 9)
    - 15. Subject Index, March 31, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Wirth, Conrad L. and others, Adirondack Mountains National Park, 1967 (Box 9)